



Alison Tahiri

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alison-tahiri-0421b2205/

Website: https://www.alisontahiri.com/
Website: https://github.com/AlisonTahiri

ABOUT ME

Hi there! I'm Alison Tahiri, a front-end developer with over 3 years of experience, out of which 2 years were focused on working with React. I've been a part of various projects, making websites and full-on web apps. I'm naturally curious and love solving problems. Making things look great on the screen is something I really enjoy.

Besides coding, I like traveling, watching movies, and playing or watching football. Oh, and I'm also learning to play the guitar in my free time!

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front end developer

Wolf Technologies [03/01/2022 - Current]

City: Tirana
Country: Albania

- Mentor and lead junior team members.
- Create innovative solutions that follow best practices and that others understand.
- Collaborate with other team members to achieve our targeted results.
- Consult with other front end developers about libraries that could be best suited to our project.

Web developer

Self employed [01/03/2020 – Current]

City: Tirana **Country:** Albania

- Create static websites using HTML, CSS, JS or Nextjs.
- Collaborate to some small projects and added some features as requested.
- Convert some old websites to Nextjs and/or implemented best practises for an above 90 lighthouse performance.
- Add google tag manager to websites to check user interaction.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Web Development Path

CodeCademy [01/06/2020 - 15/12/2020]

City: New York

Country: United States

Website: https://www.codecademy.com

Bachelor in Management

SUNY [15/09/2007 - 10/06/2011]

City: Albany

Country: United States

Website: https://www.sunyempire.edu/

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Albanian

Other language(s):

English Italian

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C2 LISTENING C2 READING C1 WRITING B1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C2 SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

Turkish German

LISTENING B1 READING B1 WRITING B1 LISTENING A2 READING A2 WRITING A2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B1 SPOKEN INTERACTION B1 SPOKEN PRODUCTION A2 SPOKEN INTERACTION A2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Frameworks

React|s / Next|s

Scripting languages

Javascript / Typescript

State Management

React / React Hooks / React Query / Redux

Page Structure

HTML

Styling

CSS / Tailwind / shadon / Material UI / Chakra UI

Version Control

Git (Github / Gitlab)

Testing

Jest / React Testing Library